# ISHMAEL KIPKOECH.

PO Box 13 – 20404 Ndanai · 0727530800 ishasir05@gmail.com https://github.com/pyish

I am a skilled ICT officer with over one year of experience in Information / Network Security, systems administration, network administration, IT Project implementation and ICT support providing solutions to support overall corporate strategic goals. I am equipped with the ability to plan, install, configure and optimize the IT infrastructure to consistently achieve high availability and performance. I am entrusted to ensure that day-to-day running of ICT processes are running well to realize company's business continuity. I am currently looking to secure a position in a fast-paced environment as IT officer with a goal to develop, implement, secure and support on ICT solutions.

#### SKILLS

- Network Administration and security
- IT Help desk; both remote and local.
- Windows Server administration.
- Network monitoring: Wire shark.
- Access controls
- Proficient in Microsoft office: Excel, power point, Word.
- Web penetration
- IT Security with Esset endpoint security implementation, and Windows Endpoint Manager.
- IT Project management

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### MARCH 2020 - TO DATE

#### FREELANCE IT SUPPORT, WEB-DEVELOPER.

My roles:

- 1. Troubleshooting laptops, desktops, printers on mobile basis.
- 2. Application support; Outlook mails, Microsoft Teams, Microsoft office, One Drive.
- 3. Advise on procurement of IT equipment
- 4. Front-end web development
- 5. Back-end web developemt
- 6. UI and UX design.
- 7. PC Hardware maintenance

#### **MAY 2019-SEPTEMBER 2019**

#### IT INTERN, SWAHILI POT HUB (SPH)

Worked with SwahilipotHub Mombasa as an intern as per the school requirement and was tasked with duties that actually helped me grow in the IT field

My roles included:

- 1. Provide technical assistance by responding to technical queries/problems (e.g. IT equipment and network) and consultations.
- 2. Provide onsite diagnostic, troubleshooting and assessment of technical problems.
- 3. Support and ensure proper roll-out and installation of new system updates/versions by co\_workers.
- 4. Collaboration on online platforms to develop and deploy software through Git and Github.
- 5. Prepare technical reports as needed.
- 6. Assembling of new computers.
- 7. Wi-Fi installation and cabling.

#### **EDUCATION AND PROFESSIONAL ACHIEVEMENTS**

MARCH 2021 - MAY 2021

Azure Developer Associate.

**AUGUST 2017 - NOV 2019** 

COMPUTER SCIENCE, PWANI UNIVERSITY.

Graduated with Credit 1. I specialized in Web-Development and information security.

**JUNE - JULY 2019** 

CISCO NETWORKING ACADEMY,

Attained a certification in networking essentials.

### REFEREES

## Professional Referees

Audrey Julia Mbogho Associate professor USIU- Nairobi ambogho@usiu.ac.ke. walegwa@gmail.com. +254703455867 Michael Onyango Member of The Board of Advisors Africa Blockchain Institute miconyango@gmail.com +254733 603 494 Benjamin Kosgei IT Support Bajaj-Kenya – Nairobi. benkosgei25@gmail +254723 684 250